<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Image Matching | Mingkun&#39;s homepage</title>
    <link>https://mingkunyang.github.io/tag/image-matching/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mingkunyang.github.io/tag/image-matching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Image Matching</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mingkunyang.github.io/images/icon_hu786fa58ccadddb09b05070c28e40422f_10189_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Image Matching</title>
      <link>https://mingkunyang.github.io/tag/image-matching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>MetricNet: A Loop Closure Detection Method for Appearance Variation using Adaptive Weighted Similarity Matrix</title>
      <link>https://mingkunyang.github.io/preprint/metricnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mingkunyang.github.io/preprint/metricnet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loop Closure Detection (LCD), also known as visual place recognition, provides extra information that &lt;strong&gt;robot has visited this area before&lt;/strong&gt;. This constrain assists the positioning system to &lt;strong&gt;reduce the pose estimation error&lt;/strong&gt; by following optimization algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contribution&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed MetricNet contains two blocks: 1) feature extraction leveraging &lt;strong&gt;deep learning&lt;/strong&gt;; 2) similarity measurement with &lt;strong&gt;adaptive weight&lt;/strong&gt;. As an &lt;strong&gt;end-to-end&lt;/strong&gt; loop closure detector, MetricNet is trained by minimizing the binary cross-entropy (BCE) consisting of label and calculated similarity score.
The contributions can be summarized into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effective feature selection and adaptive similarity matrix&lt;/strong&gt;: The learning-based feature extraction exploits spatial information. Inspired by inverse documentary frequency (IDF), a channel weight mechanism is devised to distil features that are effective for image matching. In terms of similarity calculation, it considers the link between diagonal and off-diagonal elements of similarity matrix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accurate and robust detection performance&lt;/strong&gt;: Extensive experiments reveal that MetricNet outperforms both learning-based and conventional approaches, especially under the condition with distinct apperrance changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
