<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PDR | Mingkun&#39;s homepage</title>
    <link>https://mingkunyang.github.io/tag/pdr/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mingkunyang.github.io/tag/pdr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PDR</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mingkunyang.github.io/images/icon_hu786fa58ccadddb09b05070c28e40422f_10189_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>PDR</title>
      <link>https://mingkunyang.github.io/tag/pdr/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Pedestrian Tracking Terminal Based on Adaptive Zero Velocity Update</title>
      <link>https://mingkunyang.github.io/publication/real-time-pdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mingkunyang.github.io/publication/real-time-pdr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Inertial Map Matching for Indoor Positioning using Architectural Constraints</title>
      <link>https://mingkunyang.github.io/preprint/map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mingkunyang.github.io/preprint/map/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the self-contained navigation systems, the accurate &lt;strong&gt;initial position&lt;/strong&gt;, as the prior knowledge, is crucial for real-world task. Whereas, most existing systems rely on the external signals to achieve initialization, which is contrary to the original intention of positioning whithout pre-installed infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contribution&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed algorithm requires 2D plane map, foot-mounted inertial data, hand-held shot images, realizing a real self-contained navigation system. From the topological points in the maps, the trajectory of pedestrian can be selected via three steps: 1) cursory selection by &lt;strong&gt;ZUPT-aided INS&lt;/strong&gt; generates several candidate paths; 2) &lt;strong&gt;door detection and matching&lt;/strong&gt; excludes some trails further; 3) the final result is decided by a &lt;strong&gt;Siamese Network&lt;/strong&gt; matching the spatial structure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symmetrical-Net: Adaptive Zero Velocity Detection for ZUPT-Aided Pedestrian Navigation System</title>
      <link>https://mingkunyang.github.io/publication/symmetrical-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mingkunyang.github.io/publication/symmetrical-net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zero velocity detection selects the phase that &lt;strong&gt;foot is anchored to the ground&lt;/strong&gt; from the whole gait of pedestrian. As the vital part of zero velocity update (ZUPT), it &lt;strong&gt;triggers the error-state Kalman Filter (ESKF)&lt;/strong&gt; to modify the position estimated by pedestrian dead reckoning (PDR).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contribution&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The characteristics of proposed Symmetrical-Net, as an adaptive zero velocity detector, contain: 1) leveraging &lt;strong&gt;RCNNs&lt;/strong&gt; extracts the features from waveform image of inertial data, and derives connections among consecutive sampling points; 2) Two identical RCNNs branches are &lt;strong&gt;assembled in a symmetrical shape&lt;/strong&gt;, analysing the raw IMU readings berfore and after the undetermined time instant. The contributions can be summarized into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robust and adaptive zero velocity detection&lt;/strong&gt;: Compared with the fixed threshold detector, the proposed Symmetrical-Net can &lt;strong&gt;adaptively calculate the probability&lt;/strong&gt; of being stationary, conserving the manual labour to fine tune the threshold. It also outperforms other competing adaptive detectors, which is attributed to &lt;strong&gt;considering contextual information&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;extended observation scope&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accurate and robust pedestrian tracking&lt;/strong&gt;: Performance of Symmetrical-Net makes a profound &lt;strong&gt;impact on the trajectory reconstruction of the ZUPT-aided INS system&lt;/strong&gt;. Extensive experiments reveals that the navigation system, assisted with proposed detector, maintains high-accuracy positioning &lt;strong&gt;under various individuals in three motion&lt;/strong&gt; (walking, fast walking, and running).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Research of Stance-Phase Detection to Improve ZUPT-Aided Pedestrian Navigation System</title>
      <link>https://mingkunyang.github.io/publication/iscas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mingkunyang.github.io/publication/iscas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;GPS-denied&lt;/strong&gt; environment, inertial navigation system is the justifiable and general solution because it &lt;strong&gt;do not require installation of infrastructure beforehand&lt;/strong&gt;. Nevertheless, the inertial navigation system (INS) calculates the relative displacement of an object that will result in &lt;strong&gt;accumulated errors&lt;/strong&gt; due to the sensors’ drift. Under the assumption that the velocity is zero when foot is on the ground, ZUPT-aided INS modify the positioning error leveraging this pseudo-measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contribution&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contribution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper improve the ZUPT-aided INS in two aspects: 1) By considering the zero velocity detecion as a hypothesis-testing problem, we propose a new test statistic; 2) To avoid excessive modification of heading angle (yaw), an asymptotic ZUPT is devised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accurate zero velocity detection&lt;/strong&gt;: This paper takes the &lt;strong&gt;difference value&lt;/strong&gt; of gyroscope as the test statistic, which makes the wave more sharper. The proposed method enable zero velocity detecion to maintain its accuracy &lt;strong&gt;in high-dynamic motion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stable attitude modification&lt;/strong&gt;: The heading angle, with zero velocity update, is prone to deviation, because the excessive yaw error estimation by KF at the initial update. Therefore, the &lt;strong&gt;attenuation factor&lt;/strong&gt; is applied to the pseudo-measurement, which alleviates the yaw fluctuation after update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
